hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
trying to find the area of this blue
region if you want to try it on your own
pause it right now cuz I'm going to
solve it in 3 2 one first I'm noticing
we can split this up in a couple
different ways and I want to focus on
this part right here let's get rid of
the question mark and continue this line
right here so let's call this portion X
and then since 28 is double the 14 this
blue portion would be 2X and now that
we've introduced this line we can also
split it up this way next let's focus on
this portion right here called this side
of the purple rectangle Y and then 105
is 3 * 35 so this would be 3 y so now
let's split this up we know that all of
this stuff is going to be 1/3 of all of
this stuff so we can set up a proportion
on top it would be this whole area which
would be x + 14 + 35 and on bottom it
would be this whole area which would be
2x + 28 + 21 + 105 now let's clean this
up on top here we can do 14 + 35 to give
us 49 and then on bottom the 28 + 21 is
also 49 and then 49 + 105 is 154 next we
can cross multiply we get 3 * the
quantity x + 49 is equal to 1 * thean 2x
+ 154 and then we can distribute this
three to both of these terms 3 * X is 3x
and 3 * 49 is 147 and then on the right
hand side this 1 isn't doing anything so
we have 2X + 154 now we have an x on
both sides of the equation let's get all
the the X's to one side we can do that
by subtracting 2x from both sides of the
equation after we do this we'll have an
x on this side so let's get rid of this
147 by subtracting 147 from both sides
these two 147's will cancel each other
out and these two 2 XS will cancel each
other out we end up with 3x - 2x is
equal to X and 154 - 147 is 7 x is equal
to 7 so now we can come back up here and
in the place of the X we can plug in
seven and in the place of the 2x we can
plug in 14 and 7 + 14 is equal to 21 so
the area of the blue region is equal to
21 so our question mark is equal to 21
square units this is the answer to our
question let's put a box around it I
think this problem was brilliant
speaking of brilliant let's talk about
brilliant brilliant has thousands of
lessons to choose from and all of them
are interactive you learn by doing I
really enjoyed this course on scientific
thinking it starts with simple machines
like gears and pulley and then it
eventually worked up to Einstein's
special theory of relativity when my
favorite parts were all the fun thought
experiment questions for example if we
have this distance time graph where the
y- AIS is time and years and the x-axis
is distance in light years so while
you're at the Space Rock concert a rumor
is spread that the staral concert in 2
years is not going to be any good and
the question is asking will the negative
rumor affect the attendance of the
staral concert in 2 years and the answer
is no because while the staral concert
is 2 years in the future the distance is
three light years away so the news of of
the rumor would not even reach anybody
who's going to attend this concert I'm
struggling to explain it in just one
sentence if you want to go through it
yourself brilliant currently has a free
30-day trial visit brilliant.org Andy or
check out the link in the description
you can also get 20% off an annual
premium plan if you wanted to go through
this one the name of the course is
scientific thinking how exciting